<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Poulpix&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.poulpix.fr/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Poulpix&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 09:54:22 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.poulpix.fr/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hosting</title>
      <link>http://blog.poulpix.fr/posts/hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 09:54:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.poulpix.fr/posts/hosting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As it&amp;rsquo;s a tech blog, let&amp;rsquo;s first have a look at the hosting stack !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be disappointed, no big deal here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is hosted on GitHub Pages, the free static hosting solution from GitHub. I am using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a static blog engine. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know it, have a look, it&amp;rsquo;s awesome ! No need for SQL server, or backend server (php or others).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each post is deployed through GitHub Actions, if you are curious, just go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/poolpix/blog&#34;&gt;the repository of my blog&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s open. Of course, because there is nothing to hide, it&amp;rsquo;s only blog posts that are available on the web anyway (also, GitHub pages is free only for public repos :D)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://blog.poulpix.fr/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 10:02:48 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.poulpix.fr/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Poulpix&amp;rsquo;s Blog !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am Valentin, currently working as a &amp;ldquo;DevOps&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a very common word in the IT world now, it should represent a whole philosophy of integration between Dev teams and Ops teams, but as a job it&amp;rsquo;s actually more about modern System Administration, with Cloud part, CDN part, CI/CD part, observability part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this blog I will share interesting news (DevOps, Site Reliability Engineering, Systems Administration), or some cool tasks from my working environment (currently web), that could help mates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
